we're gonna turn up the heat with this
one today running on concrete may not be
the best for your joints and let's be
honest your typical stationary bike and
treadmill can be a little bit boring at
times
now i promise you won't be bored with
the assault air bike but you might want
to be tapping out after just a few quick
minutes i've been using this beast for
quite a while so i think you know the
deal it's time for me to share my
experience with y'all
[Music]
what's up everybody it's jake back in
the barbing garage gym with another
review locked and loaded for y'all today
i've got the assault air bike in this
video i'm going to tell you everything
you need to know about this exercise
bike from the price the features some
pros and cons you might experience while
working out with it and of course who
should or maybe should not buy one of
these but before i get really going
today we've reviewed a lot of exercise
bikes on barbin.com if you want to
browse our best list just go ahead and
search barbin best exercise bikes you
can find out for yourself which ones we
like the best
okay so what do i like about the assault
air bike well the arms actually move so
it's going to require your upper body to
get into it during your workout this is
a great way for you to simply hit a
quick upper body workout the display is
loaded with interval workouts as well as
goal workouts that will help keep you
motivated plus you know since you are
required to use your upper body you're
gonna be burning a lot of extra calories
here and i know i said we're turning up
the heat and that's still true but this
is actually a fan bike and because of
that you're gonna catch a little bit of
a breeze while you're working out that
might actually help cool you off a
little bit and because there is a set of
wheels located on the front of the bike
you can easily move it around your space
okay so what about those potential cons
that you might experience with the
assault air bike well this is a fan bike
as i just said so it's kind of loud
while you're working out and that really
just may not be ideal for everyone you
don't have any bluetooth capabilities to
stream workouts or listen any music with
speakers
you can find both of those features and
some other competition bikes out there
and 750 dollars may seem like a chunk of
change considering there's not a ton of
features and overall it just kind of has
a little bit of a different feel
compared to your typical exercise bike
you'll find at a gym so that also might
not be for everyone
[Music]
so in terms of pricing the assault air
bike is listed right around 750 and if
you're not crazy about the wind blowing
in your face from the fan you can get a
little screen protector it's going to
cost you about 50 bucks or so once you
tack on your shipping and handling and
of course taxes it's gonna cost you
right around 875 now
that's a lot of money don't get me wrong
but when you compare the price of this
you know to peloton for example
you're saving a good amount of money
now there's also some that are cheaper
than this as well so
really boils down to personal preference
you know if you want a bike that has
more features you can pay more money to
find that or you know you can even save
more money and get a bike that's more
simple than this one right here now i'm
a big stationary bike kind of guy i
don't really like running on concrete
treadmill tends to be a little bit
boring for me and i gotta say you know i
think this is well worth the money
because it tends to kick my butt every
single time i go to get on it
if you're interested in the upgraded
version of the air bike well there's a
couple out there for you there's the air
bike pro and the air bike elite so let's
talk about the air bike pro it's going
to cost you around a thousand dollars
this is going to include an improved lcd
display with bluetooth capabilities for
your phone or fitness tracker as well as
being compatible with the assault
fitness app
it has a 7 year warranty on the frame as
well as a three-year manufacturer
warranty on all the parts it also comes
with 11 height adjustments on the seat
to go with six front to back adjustments
now if you're interested in that air
bike elite that's going to cost you over
1300 bucks that's going to feature the
exact same lcd display as the pro but it
also has custom programming options it
features a bulkier steel frame the
windscreen is built into it the seat is
bigger and it also has a 10 year
manufacturer warranty on the frame to go
along with that three-year warranty on
the parts as well as eight front to back
adjustments on the seat to go along with
those 11 height adjustments
all right so now in terms of the build
the assault air bike does have a steel
frame that i mentioned earlier as well
as a powder coat finish on it the fan is
25 inches the arms are movable and
they're bound to experience some wear
and tear over time but honestly i think
as long as you just take the proper care
of it and keep everything nice and clean
it's gonna be built to last the wheels
on the front make it really easy to move
it around your personal space and this
model does feature a five-year warranty
now in terms of operating everything
there's a chain just like you would find
on a bicycle your standard bike it's
gonna power the fan it's connected to
the wheels that's what drives everything
and makes it move now in terms of the
features i already talked about the
chain powers everything the lcd display
is pretty simple and i actually kind of
like that pretty straightforward you
have seven different workouts for you to
choose from right here it's gonna help
keep you motivated also offers some
versatility to your workouts the seat is
nice and padded right here it's not
uncomfortable to sit on during those
long bike rides it has 10 different
height adjustments to go along with four
different front to back adjustments
pretty cool feature here is that the
harder you pedal on this bike the harder
it's going to be so the harder you pedal
the resistance is in fact going to
increase on you and make it more
difficult and because the arms are
movable once again it's going to allow
you to get your upper body involved in
your workout it's going to help you burn
some extra calories and you can even put
your feet on the pegs that are located
on either side of the bike so you can
take your legs out of the equation
completely and just focus on your upper
body
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the lcd display
in a little further detail now as i
mentioned it's pretty straightforward
which i personally really like that just
straight to business now you have seven
different programs for you to choose
from you have a 2010 interval a 1020
interval your own custom interval you
can work with a target time a target
distance target calories and even target
heart rate now all that is really cool
it's also nice that the display is going
to track your heart rate your rotations
per minute your time traveled your
distance traveled and your overall speed
plus
you're not required to use a cord to
power this display at all which is
really nice to me personally because
working out outside is one of my
favorite things to do
you can definitely take this outside
with you if you want to do so
[Music]
all right y'all let's do a quick walk
around with the assault air bike as i
mentioned you do have a set of wheels
located at the front of this bike it's
going to make it really easy for you to
move it around your personal space and
how i go about doing that that is simply
walk around back right here
reach over grab the base right here
simply lean it forward and you can
easily move it around your space now i
don't know exactly how much this weighs
i'd say probably around 70 pounds or so
maybe not too much more than that which
is actually a pretty solid number it's
gonna make it pretty easy for you to
move it around now as i said you do have
four different front to back adjustments
for this seat pad and to do that there's
a knob underneath right here just pull
down
it's going to allow you to move it front
and back
and you can lock it into place
the same goes for the height adjustments
you have 10 different ones for you to
work with
same thing pull out on this knob
raise it up raise it down
there's a really good chance that this
is compatible for
every single athlete out there which is
really nice now in terms of actually
operating the bike i'm going to show you
how it's done it's really easy and to do
that just hop on it
start pedaling
as you can tell it's kind of wild and
not everybody's gonna be crazy about
that i personally like the fan it does
give me a bit of a breeze while i'm
working out and i also really like how
this bike gets harder the harder that i
try and you know once again you can
operate this with just your arms as you
can see i have my feet on the pegs right
now they just simply fit right there
and you just start moving your arms
once again you really can tell how loud
that is but i don't really mind it and
this is a really good way for you to get
a upper body workout in if you really
want to do so get it done really quick
now lcd display talked about it earlier
you have seven different programs for
you to choose from
all you got to do is select which one
you want to go with it's going to give
you a little bit of a countdown that way
you can get your body in the right
position is also get mentally prepared
because this thing kicks my butt every
time i get on it and it'll count down
and kick right in and you'll just follow
all the prompts that are on the display
now
really cool thing here is that you're
not tied in to an outlet to a cord all
you need is two double-a batteries to
plug in underneath right here it's gonna
power everything and you're good to go
[Music]
okay so who should purchase the assault
air bike well if you're looking for a
solid cardio workout without needing to
run i think this is a really good option
for you to consider it's gonna make you
sweat it's gonna make you burn a lot of
calories and since you can't operate it
with just using the arms it's also a
great way to get an upper body workout
in
somebody who's not wanting to spend a
couple thousand dollars on a high
quality exercise bike this is a really
good option for you to consider and
since it does have a set of wheels you
can move it around your space easily and
it doesn't require a power cord so if
you're able to do so you can take this
bad boy outside and get an awesome
workout in
[Music]
okay so what about those people who
might not want to purchase the assault
air bike while it's definitely cheaper
than some big name brands out there
you're still spending around 800
on an exercise bike and if that's
something you just simply can't or don't
want to do you can definitely find some
cheaper alternatives out there
if you're interested in your exercise
bike to have more features well there's
a good amount out there that do in fact
have speakers built into the display as
well as the ability to stream workouts
directly on the display so if that's
something you want i'd also consider
looking elsewhere maybe even consider
one of the upgraded versions of the air
bike and not everybody's going to be
crazy about having a fan located on the
front of their exercise bike
that's going to be annoying for you if
you don't want to listen to that loud
noise all the time then i'd suggest
going after a standard stationary bike
all right well that's a wrap for today's
review over the assault air bike i think
this is a great way for you to get a
solid cardio workout into your workout
routine the movable arms are gonna force
your upper body to get into that workout
and you can even operate it with just
your arms for an upper body workout the
lcd display has seven different workouts
for you to choose from and the harder
you pedal the harder your workout is
gonna be which is really cool the fan on
the front of this bike could be a bit of
an annoyance for some people because it
is gonna make your workout kind of loud
plus there are some bikes out there that
do have more features than this one
right here plus there's also some that
are cheaper than the air bike thanks for
watching fam i hope this video was
really helpful and i was able to answer
any questions that you may have over the
assault air bike as always stay posted
for my next review but for now you
should definitely head over to
barbin.com to read more about this
product right here just search bar bend
assault air bike review our article is
going to pull right up for you and you
can read about everything i talked about
here today now i'm going to go sweat
i'll see y'all next time
[Music]
what's up